Mss.530.1.Ar2.2 Mss.530.1.Ar2.2
American Philosophical Society
- Papers, 1923-1959; Van Vleck, J. H., (John Hasbrouck), 1899-1980
  - Letter to [John H.] Van Vleck, March 31, 1927; 10-3/4x8-1/2; Kramers, Hendrik Anthony, 1894-1952
    Utrecht, A.L.S. 1p. (see Archive for the History of Quantum Physics. No.2.) Thanks for his letter on the lack of posts for Niessen.
  - Letter to [John H.] Van Vleck, April 15, 1927; 11x8-1/2; Kronig, R. (Ralph), 1904-
    New York, A.L.S. 6p. (see Archive for the History of Quantum Physics.No.2.) Disagrees with him on his paper regarding"the validity of the formula for the magnetic movement of atoms and molecules induced by a magnetic field," and explains Refers to Darwin.
  - Letter to [John H.] Van Vleck, April 19, 1927; 11x7-1/4; Debye, Peter J. W. (Peter Josef William), 1884-
    Madison, A.L.S. 1p. (see Archive for the History of Quantum Physics.No.2.) Thanks for his publication on physics and has already used the main features of it in a lecture.
  - Letter to [Ralph de Laer] Kronig, April 24, 1927; 11x8-1/2; Van Vleck, J. H. (John Hasbrouck), 1899-
    Typed L.S. 7p.and 3p.duplicated. (see Archive for the History of Quantum Physics. No.2.) Concerning the measurement of angular momentum measured with reference to fixed muclei. Refers to Debye.
  - Letter to [John H.] Van Vleck, May 4, 1927; 10-1/2x8; Kronig, R. (Ralph), 1904-
    New York, A.L.S. 2p. (see Archive for the History of Quantum Physics. No.2.) Concerning molecules and atoms as expressed in his last letter.
  - Letter to [John H. Van Vleck, May 27, 1927; 6-3/4x5-1/4; Slater, John C. (John Clarke), 1900-1976
    A.L.S. 4p. Incomplete. (see Archive for the History of Quantum Physics. No.2.) On quantum mechanics. Is"computing helium!!" Glad he will be at Palo Alto, California.
  - Letter to [John H.] Van Vleck, Aug. 25, 1927; 11x8-1/2; Birge, Raymond T. (Raymond Thayer), 1887-
    Berkeley, Cal., Typed L.S. 1p. (see Archive for the History of Quantum Physics. No.2.) Comments on publications on quantum theories with comments of certain men.
  - Letter to Wheeler P. Davey, State College, Penna., Aug. 26, 1927; 10-1/2x8; Van Vleck, J. H. (John Hasbrouck), 1899-
    Typed L. 1p. Incomplete. Carbon copy. (see Archive for the History of Quantum Physics. No.2.) Forwards article and makes comments on what can be omitted, etc.
  - Letter to J[ohn] H. Van Vleck, Minneapolis, Minn., Sept. 27, 1927; 11x8-1/2; Rodebush, Worth Huff, b. 1887
    Orbana, Ill., Typed L.S. 1p. (see Archive for the History of Quantum Physics. No.2.) Asks a question based upon his paper on dielectric constant.
  - Letter to [John H.] Van [Vleck], Nov. 13, 1927; 11x8-1/2; Slater, John C. (John Clarke), 1900-1976
    A.L.S. 2p. (see Archive for the History of Quantum Physics. No.2.) Concerning his work on helium. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to G. E. Stechert and Co., New York, Nov. 28, 1927; 11x8-1/2; Van Vleck, J. H. (John Hasbrouck), 1899-
    L. 1p. Incomplete. Carbon copy. (see Archive for the History of Quantum Physics. No.2.) Concerning the possibility of a reprint of his work on "Quantum Principles and Line Spectra."
  - Letter to J[ohn] H. Van Vleck, Minneapolis, Minn., Dec. 7, 1927; 11x8-1/2; National Research Council
    Washington, D.C., Typed L.S.: Dayton C. Miller, by Nera E. Reynolds. 1p. (see Archive for the History of Quantum Physics. No.2.) Will make 300 reprints of his "Quantum Principles and Line Spectra."
  - Letter to [John H.] Van Vleck, Jan. 13, 1928; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Kemble, Edwin C. (Edwin Crawford), 1889-
    Cambridge, Mass., A.L.S. 2p. (see Archives for the History of Quantum Physics. No.2.) His studies on atomic matter of oxygen.
  - Letter to [Edwin C.] Kemble, Jan. 19, 1928; 11x8-1/2; Van Vleck, J. H. (John Hasbrouck), 1899-
    Typed L. 3p. Carbon copy. (see Archive for the History of Quantum Physics. No.2.) States his "contraction of the doublets." Asks him to see if it conflicts with present work. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to J[ohn] H. Van Vleck, Minneapolis, Minn., Jan. 25, 1928; 10-1/2x8; Kemble, Edwin C. (Edwin Crawford), 1889-
    Cambridge, Mass., Typed L.S. 2p. (see Archive for the History of Quantum Physics. No.2.) Congratulates him on his formula for the "doublet contraction." His work on the subject is now worthless. Friendly letter.
  - Telegram to [John H.] Van Vleck, Minneapolis, Minn., Feb. 1, 1928; 6-1/2x8; Dennison, David Mathias, 1900-
    Ann Arbor, Mich., D. 1p. (see Archive for the History of Quantum Physics. No.2.) Concerning an article which he believes "a half page addition to proof will correct" on computations.
  - Letter to Paul D. Foote, Washington, D.C., Feb. 2, 1928; 11x8-1/2; Van Vleck, J. H. (John Hasbrouck), 1899-
    Typed L. 1p. Carbon copy. Mutilated (see Archive for the History of Quantum Physics. No.2.) Since quantum theory progresses so rapidly, he has had to rewrite a large part of a chapter, even though in galley, which he returns.
  - Letter to [Edwin C.] Kemble, Feb. 12, 1928; 11x8-1/2; Van Vleck, J. H. (John Hasbrouck), 1899-
    Typed L. 2p. Carbon copy. (see Archive for the History of Quantum Physics. No.2.) Concerning the formula for "narrow doublets" as worked out with Hill. Concerning Hill's future as a graduate student. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to J[ohn] H. Van Vleck, Minneapolis, Minn., Feb. 16, 1928; 10-1/2x8; Kemble, Edwin C. (Edwin Crawford), 1889-
    Cambridge, Mass., Typed L.S. 2p. (see Archive for the History of Quantum Physics. No.2.) Concerning possible position for Hill. Quantum theory.
  - Letter to Wheeler P. Davey, State College, Penna., Feb. 16, 1928; 11x8-1/2; Van Vleck, J. H. (John Hasbrouck), 1899-
    Typed L. 2p. Carbon copy. (see Archive for the History of Quantum Physics. No.2.) Forwards his manuscript and states that the quantum theory "is now getting in a more settled condition."
  - Letter to [John H.] Van Vleck, Feb. 24, 1928; 10-3/4x8-1/2; Kramers, Hendrik Anthony, 1894-1952
    Utrecht, A.L.S. 1p. (see Archive for the History of Quantum Physics. No.2.) Plans to lecture in the U.S. and would like to visit Minnesota to lecture and talk with him.
  - Letter to [Robert S.] Mulliken, March 25, 1928; 11x8-1/2; Van Vleck, J. H. (John Hasbrouck), 1899-
    Typed L. 2p. Carbon copy. (see Archive for the History of Quantum Theory. No.2.) Asks if certain work has been done in quantum physics and explains his need to know.
  - Letter to [John H.] Van [Vleck], March 28, 1928; 11x8-1/2; Mulliken, Robert Sanderson
    New York, A.L.S. 6p. (see Archive for the History of Quantum Physics.No.2.) Concerning O-type doubling and related theory.
  - Letter to [John H.] Van [Vleck], April 11, 1928; 11x8-1/2; Mulliken, Robert Sanderson
    New York, A.L.S. 4p. (see Archive for the History of Quantum Physics. No.2.) Concerning "magnetic susceptibilities." Concerning a problem in quantum physics.
  - Letter to E[dwin] C. Kemble, April 19, 1928; 11x8-1/2; Van Vleck, J. H. (John Hasbrouck), 1899-
    Cambridge, Mass., Typed L. 1p. Carbon copy. (see Archive for the History of Quantum Physics. No.2.) Congratulations on his Guggenheim. Concerning his book on quantum physics.
    Not Found: 4/2011
    General note
    Unlocated 5/2011
  - Letter to [Hendrik A.] Kramers, April 22, 1928; 11x8-1/2; Van Vleck, J. H. (John Hasbrouck), 1899-
    Typed L. 2p. Carbon copy. (see Archive for the History of Quantum Theory. No.2.) Extends invitation for him to visit Minnesota. Comments on trip to the West Coast.
  - Letter to [John H.] Van Vleck, April 24, 1928; 8x5; Kramers, Hendrik Anthony, 1894-1952
    Toronto, Can., A.L.S. 2p. (see Archive for the History of Quantum Physics. No.2.) Hopes he can visit Minnesota and lecture.
  - Letter to [Ralph de L. Kronig?, April 28, 1928?; 11x8-1/2; Van Vleck, J. H. (John Hasbrouck), 1899-
    Typed L. 1p. Carbon copy. Incomplete for this is marked: [Page] 4. (see Arhive for the History of Quantum Physics. No.2.) Concerning quantum theory.
  - Letter to [John H.] Van Vleck, April 28, 1928; 8x5; Kramers, Hendrik Anthony, 1894-1952
    Toronto, A.L.S. 2p. (see Archive for the History of Quantum Physics. No.2.) Can visit and lecture at Minnesota and states dates and hours.
  - Letter to [Ralph de Laer] Kronig, April 28, 1928; 11x8-1/2; Van Vleck, J. H. (John Hasbrouck), 1899-
    Typed L. 2p. Carbon copy. (see Archive for the History of Quantum Physics. No.2.) States that his work may overlap Kronig's, but explains work of self and Hill. Quantum theory.
  - Letter to [Hendrik A.] Kramers, May 15, 1928; 11x8-1/2; Van Vleck, J. H. (John Hasbrouck), 1899-
    Typed L. 1p. Carbon copy. (see Archive for the History of Quantum Theory. No.2.) Asks if he could lecture so that appeal would be made to chemists as well as physicists.
  - Letter to [John H.] Van [Vleck], May 21, 1928; 11x8-1/2; Mulliken, Robert Sanderson
    New York, A.L.S.: Mully. 3p. (see Archive for the History of Quantum Physics No. 2.) His work on O-type doubling. Comments and questions on O-type doubling.
  - Letter to W[orth] H. Rodebush, Urbana, Ill., May 21, 1928; 11x8-1/2; Van Vleck, J. H. (John Hasbrouck), 1899-
    Typed L. 1p. Carbon copy. (see Archive for the History of Quantum Physics. No.2.) Comments on the atom in the "S-state."
  - Letter to [John H.] Van [Vleck], May 25, 1928; 11x8-1/2; Mulliken, Robert Sanderson
    New York, A.L.S. 2p. (see Archive for the History of Quantum Physics. No.2.) Forwards article and asks comments. Concerning "excited electron states."
  - Letter to [John H.] Van Vleck, May 27, 1928; 11-3/4x8-1/4; Kronig, R. (Ralph), 1904-
    Zurich, A.L.S. 2p. (see Archive for the History of Quantum Physics. No.2.) Concerning O-doubling. Comments on his work in "fine structure terms".
  - Letter to [John H.] Van Vleck, June 8, 1928; 11x8-1/2; Birge, Raymond T. (Raymond Thayer), 1887-
    Berkeley, Cal., A.L.S. 3p. (see Archive for the History of Quantum Physics. No.2.) Concerning work on the theory of molecular structure and stays that Mulliken deserves credit for work listed as "Birge and Mulliken".
  - Letter to John [C. Slater], June 8, 1928; 11x8-1/2; Van Vleck, J. H. (John Hasbrouck), 1899-
    Typed L. 1p. Carbon copy. (see Archive for the History of Quantum Physics. No.2.) Cites a new publication and asks if he [Slater] wishes to change his current article on helium.
  - Letter to [John H.] Van [Vleck], June 20, 1928; 11x8-1/2; Mulliken, Robert Sanderson
    New York, A.L.S. 2p. (see Archive for the History of Quantum Physics. No.2.) Concerning O-type doubling.
  - Letter to "Dear Mully" [Robert S. Mulliken], June 23, 1928; 11x8-/2; Van Vleck, J. H. (John Hasbrouck), 1899-
    Typed L. 7p. Carbon copy. (see Archive for the History of Quantum Physics. No.2.) Wants them to publish on O-type doubling together. Comments on various questions of quantum theory.
  - Letter to [Ralph de L.] Kronig, June 24, 1928; 11x8-1/2; Van Vleck, J. H. (John Hasbrouck), 1899-
    Typed L.S. 2p. Carbon copy. (see Archive for the History of Quantum Physics. No.2.) Concerning work on electron spin and asks if he would like to publish together.
  - Letter to [John H.] Van Vleck, June 30, 1928; 11-1/2x8-1/4; Kronig, R. (Ralph), 1904-
    Zurich, A.L.S. 2p. (see Archive for the History of Quantum Physics. No.2.) Writes on his computations on the "perturbation matrix which give rise to the splitting [doublet splitting]."
  - Letter to [John H.] Van [Vleck], June 30, 1928; 11x8-1/2; Mulliken, Robert Sanderson
    Ann Arbor, Mich., A.L.S. Mully. 4p. (see Archive for the History of Quantum Physics No.2.) O-type doubling. Will revise his article. Comments on work of Birge.
  - Letter to [Edwin C.] Kemble, July 9, 1928; 11x8-1/2; Van Vleck, J. H. (John Hasbrouck), 1899-
    Typed L. 2p. Carbon copy. (see Archive for the History of Quantum Physics. No.2.) Concerning a paper by Hill and self "on the rotational distortion."
  - Letter to [John H.] Van Vleck, July 11, 1928; 11-3/4x8-1/4; Kronig, R. (Ralph), 1904-
    Zürich, A.L.S. 2p. (see Archive for the History of Quantum Physics. No.2.) Concerning work on "the perturbations in bands and the predissociation of molecules" and the prospects of their publishing to gether.
  - Letter to [John H.] Van [Vleck], July 17, 1928; 11x7-1/4; Slater, John C. (John Clarke), 1900-1976
    Chicago, I11., A.L.S. 2p. (see Archive for the History of Quantum Physics. No.2.) Concerning his work on helium. Kramers is to visit.
  - Letter to [Raymond T.] Birge, July 19, 1928; 11x8-1/2; Van Vleck, J. H. (John Hasbrouck), 1899-
    Typed L. 1p. Incomplete. Carbon copy (see Archive for the History of Quantum Physics. No.2.) Concerning the publication of his table of constants.
  - Letter to [John H.] Van [Vleck], Oct. 8, 1928; 11x8-1/2; Mulliken, Robert Sanderson
    Chicago, A.L.S. 2p. (see Archive for the History of Quantum Physics.No.2.) Will visit him, but not for football. Comments on a letter of Dirac. Refers to Bohr, physics, etc.
  - Letter to P[aul] A. M. Dirac, Cambridge, Eng., Oct. 26, 1928; 11x8-1/2; Van Vleck, J. H. (John Hasbrouck), 1899-
    Typed L. 2p. Carbon copy. (see Archive for the History of Quantum Physics. No.2.) Glad he is to lecture at Minnesota and hopes the lecture will be on quantum physics.
  - Letter to [John H.] Van [Vleck], Nov. 8, [1928]; 10-1/2x8; Slater, John C. (John Clarke), 1900-1976
    A.L.S.with initials. 2p. (see Archive for the History of Quantum Physics. No.2.) Concerning a program for talks on quantum physics and comments on the men and subjects.
  - Letter to John [C. Slater], Nov. 12, 1928; 11x8-1/2; Van Vleck, J. H. (John Hasbrouck), 1899-
    Typed L. 2p. Carbon copy. (see Archive for the History of Quantum Physics. No.2.) Outlines his talk on quantum theory and comments on the rest of the program. Suggests Swann be invited to talk.
  - Letter to [John H.] Van [Vleck], Nov. 13, 1928; 113-/4x8-1/4; Kramers, Hendrik Anthony, 1894-1952
    Utrecht, A.L.S. 2p. (see Archive for the History of Quantum Physics. No.2.) Hopes Van will visit. Concerning work on the oxygen molecule. Concerning Dirac and his new ideas.
  - Letter to [John H.] Van [Vleck], Nov. 17, 1928; 11x8-1/2; Slater, John C. (John Clarke), 1900-1976
    Typed L.S.with initials. 1p. (see Archive for the History of Quantum Physics. No.2.) Concerning their talks and he wishes them to be on the "inherently statistical nature of quantum mechanics," at a meeting
  - Letter to "Dear Dana;", Nov. 20, 1928; 11x8-1/2; Van Vleck, J. H. (John Hasbrouck), 1899-
    Typed L. 1p. Carbon copy. (see Archive for the History of Quantum Physics. No.2.) Concerning reading in quantum theory.
  - Letter to [John H.] Van Vleck, Dec. 6, 1928; 7x4-1/2; Dirac, P. A. M. (Paul Adrien Maurice), 1902-1984
    Cambridge, Eng., A.L.S. 1p. (see Archive for the History of Quantum Physics. No.2.) Will begin his lectures with the transformation theory and go from there. Students will need prior quantum theory.
  - Letter to [John H.] Van Vleck, Dec. 28, 1928; 11x8-1/2; Birge, Raymond T. (Raymond Thayer), 1887-
    Berkeley, Cal., Typed L.S. 1p. (see Archive for the History of Quantum Physics. No.2.) Concerning his tables of constants and the general constants for physical science
  - Letter to [John H.] Van [Vleck], Dec. 28, 1928; 11-3/4x8-1/4; Kramers, Hendrik Anthony, 1894-1952
    Utrecht, A.L.S. 2P. (see Archive for the History of Quantum Physics. No.2.) Concerning his work on Oxygen and some problems of a student in physics.
  - The vibrations of CO2 molecule, [to John H. Van Vleck, 1928; 11x8-1/2; Dennison, David Mathias, 1900-
    ca.]. A.D. 3p. (see Archive for the History of Quantum Physics. No.2.)
  - Letter to J[ohn] H. Van Vleck, Madison, Wisc., Jan. 8, 1929; 10-1/2x8; Kennard, E. H. (Earle Hesse), b. 1885
    Ithica, New York, Typed L.S. 1p. (see Archives for the History of Quantum Physics. No.2.) Concerning a report on the symposium at the Franklin Institute on physics.
  - Letter to [John H.] Van [Vleck], Jan. 10, 1929; 11x8-1/2; Mulliken, Robert Sanderson
    Chicago, A.L.S.: Mully. 2p. (see Archive for the History of Quantum Physics No.2.) Asks for information from him or Hill about the Zeeman levels,etc.
  - Letter to E[arle] H. Kennard, Ithaca, N.Y., Jan. 14, 1929; 11x8-1/2; Van Vleck, J. H. (John Hasbrouck), 1899-
    Typed L. 3p. Carbon copy. (see Archive for the History of Quantum Physics. No.2.) Replies to questions pertaining to quantum physics.
  - Letter to Mully [Robert S. Mulliken], Jan. 15, 1929; 11x8-1/2; Van Vleck, J. H. (John Hasbrouck), 1899-
    L. 1p. Carbon copy. (see Archive for the History of Quantum Physics No.2.) Concerning his paper on various aspects of quantum theory and comments on it.
  - Letter to H[endrik] A. Kramers,Utrecht, Holland, Jan. 16, 1929; 11x8-1/2; Van Vleck, J. H. (John Hasbrouck), 1899-
    Typed L. 2p. Carbon copy. (see Archive for the History of Quantum Physics. No.2.) Comments on "matrix elements with the type of binding force" in his oxygen paper Comments on work in quantum physics.
  - Letter to Mully [Robert S. Mulliken], Feb. 14, 1929; 11x8-1/2; Van Vleck, J. H. (John Hasbrouck), 1899-
    Typed L. 4p.and 1p.equations. Carbon copy. (see Archive for History of Quantum Physics. No.2.) Lengthy comments on various questions on work in quantum physics as in certain papers which they are writing.
  - Letter to R[aymond] T. Birge, Berkeley, Cal., Feb. 19, 1929; 11x8-1/2; Van Vleck, J. H. (John Hasbrouck), 1899-
    Typed L. 1p. Carbon copy. (see Archive for the History of Quantum Physics. No.2.) Thanks for his table on constants and comments on it.
  - Letter to G[regory] Breit, Washington, D.C., Feb. 19, 1929; 11x8-1/2; Van Vleck, J. H. (John Hasbrouck), 1899-
    Typed L. 1p. Carbon copy. (see Archive for the History of Quantum Physics. No. 2.) Comments on "doubling phenomena in molecular spectroscopy. Refers to Dirac's visit. His comments on Eddington's theory of fine structure constant,value 1/136.
  - Letter to P[aul] A. M. Dirac, Cambridge, Eng., Feb. 22, 1929; 11x8-1/2; Van Vleck, J. H. (John Hasbrouck), 1899-
    Typed L. 1p. Carbon copy. (see Archive for the History of Quantum Physics. No.2.) Concerning his lecture on quantum physics. Suggestions as to the means of travelling across the U.S.
  - Letter to [John H.] Van [Vleck], Feb. 25(?), 1929; 11x8-1/2; Mulliken, Robert Sanderson
    A.L.S.: Mully. 3p. (See Archive for the History of Quantum Physics No.2.) Concerning their articles on quantum theory.
  - Letter to [Edward L.] Hill, March 18, 1929; 11x8-1/2; Van Vleck, J. H. (John Hasbrouck), 1899-
    Typed L. 2p. Carbon copy. (see Archive for the History of Quantum Physics. No.2.) Concerning the Raman effect and hopes a book will appear on it.
  - Letter to [John H.] Van [Vleck], April 1, 1929; 10-1/2x8; Breit, Gregory, 1899-
    Washington, D.C., A.L.S. 2p. (see Archive for the History of Quantum Physics.No.2.) Suggestions on a colloquia on atomic physics and Suggests Heisenberg, Dirac, Sommerfeld, Vallarta, with possible topics
  - Letter to [John H.] Van Vleck, April 1, 1929; 11x7-1/4; Hill, Edward Lee, 1904-1974
    Cambridge, Mass., A.L.S. 3p. (see Archive for the History of Quantum Physics.No.2.) Concerning the Raman effect. Concerning Heisenberg's lectures and the "small mutiny" he has stirred up in physics.
  - Letter to J[ohn] H. Van Vleck, Madison, Wisc., May 21, 1929; 11x8-1/2; Rodebush, Worth Huff, b. 1887
    Urbana, Ill., Typed L.S. 1p. (see Archive for History of Quantum Physics.No.2) Concerning the"chemical constant of hydrogen."
  - Letter to W[orth] H. Rodebush, Urbana, Ill., May 24, 1929; 11x8-1/2; Van Vleck, J. H. (John Hasbrouck), 1899-
    Typed L. 1p. Carbon copy. (see Archive for the History of Quantum Physics. No.2.) Concerning the chemical constants of hydrogen.
  - Letter to [John H.] Van Vleck, June 9, 1929; 8-1/2x5-1/4; Dirac, P. A. M. (Paul Adrien Maurice), 1902-1984
    A.L.S. 2p. (see Archive for the History of Quantum Physics. No.2.) Travelled across the U.S.on train full of Shriners. Grand Cañyon and Yosemite full of Shriners, but Yosemite empty of them now. Beautiful place.
  - Letter to [John H.] Van Vleck, June 22, 1929; 11x8-1/2; Bitter, Francis, 1902-1967
    Pasadena Cal., A.L.S. 2p. (see Archive for the History of Quantum Physics.No.2.) His apparatus for measuring the magnetic susceptibilities of gas proves Van Vleck's predictions on NO. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to G[lenn] G. Havens, June 26, [1929]; 11x8-1/2; Van Vleck, J. H. (John Hasbrouck), 1899-
    A.L.S. 1p. (see Archive for the History of Quantum Physics. No.2) Forwards his letter to Bitter on measuring magnetic susceptibilities of gas. On same sheet as: Van Vleck to Bitter; June 26, 1929.
  - Letter to Francis Bitter, Pasadena, Cal., June 26, 1929; 11x8-1/2; Van Vleck, J. H. (John Hasbrouck), 1899-
    Typed L. 1p. Carbon copy. (see Archive for the History of Quantum Physics. No.2.) Concerning his measurements of the magnetic susceptibilities of gas. Other work in the same field. On same sheet is: Van Vleck to G.G. Havens;June 26, 1929,on copy of above.
  - Letter to W[orth] H. Rodebush, Urbana, Ill., July 29, 1929; 11x8-1/2; Van Vleck, J. H. (John Hasbrouck), 1899-
    Typed L. 1p. Carbon copy. (see Archive for the History of Quantum Physics. No.2.) Concerning Fowler and his work on the chemical constant of hydrogen.
  - Letter to [John H.] Van [Vleck], Aug. 16, 1929; 8x5; Mulliken, Robert Sanderson
    A.L.S.: Mully. 3p. (see Archive for the History of Quantum Physics. No.2.) Questions concerning an equation.
  - Letter to [John H.] Van [Vleck] Leipzig, Dec. 29, 1929; 11x6-3/4; Slater, John C. (John Clarke), 1900-1976
    [ca.]. A.L.S. 4p. (see Archive for the History of Quantum Physics.No.2.) Describes Leipzig. Concerning his stay in Germany and Plans for trip home. Friendly letter.
  - Plans for study in connection with an application for a Guggenheim fellowship, [1929]; 11x8-1/2; Van Vleck, J. H. (John Hasbrouck), 1899-
    Typed D. 2p. Carbon copy. (see Archive for the History of Quantum Physics. No.2.)
  - Letter to [John H.] Van Vleck, Nov. 7, 1930; 9x7; Darwin, Charles Galton, Sir, 1887-1962
    Edinburgh, Scotland, [ca.]. A.L.S. 2p. (see Archive for the History of Quantum Physics. No.2.) Has tried to get a grant for Schlapp to work under Van Vleck.
  - Letter to J[ohn] H. Van Vleck, Madison, Wisc., Jan. 6, 1931; 11x8-1/2; Mulliken, Robert Sanderson
    Chicago, Typed L.S. 2p. (see Archive for the History of Quantum Physics. No.2.) Questions concerning work on doublets, meaning of the "magnetic moment", energy levels in a magnetic field, etc.
  - Letter to J[ohn] H. Van Vleck, Madison, Wisc., Jan. 13, 1931; 11x8-1/2; Bitter, Francis, 1902-1967
    East Pittsburgh, Pa., Typed L.S. 1p. (see Archives for the History of Quantum Physics. No.2.) Concerning the susceptibility of the salts of the iron group paper and its result.
  - Letter to [John H.] Van Vleck, April 24, 1931; 7x4-1/2; Dirac, P. A. M. (Paul Adrien Maurice), 1902-1984
    Cambridge, Eng., A.L.S. 3p. (see Archive for the History of Quantum Physics. No.2.) Asks for help to plan a trip across the U.S. Concerning Bohr and quantum physics in general.
  - Letter to [John H.] Van Vleck, June 1, 1931; 7x4-1/2; Dirac, P. A. M. (Paul Adrien Maurice), 1902-1984
    Cambridge, Eng., A.L.S. 2p. (see Archive for the History of Quantum Physics. No.2.) Concerning his travels in the U.S.
  - Letter to [John H.] Van Vleck, July 8, 1931; 7x4-1/2; Dirac, P. A. M. (Paul Adrien Maurice), 1902-1984
    Cambridge, Eng., A.L.S. 2p. (see Archive for the History of Quantum Physics. No.2.) Will extend his visit to Glacier National Park.
  - Letter to [John H.] Van Vleck, July 18, 1931; 7x4-1/2; Dirac, P. A. M. (Paul Adrien Maurice), 1902-1984
    Cambridge, Eng., A.L.S. 3p. (see Archive for the History of Quantum Physics. No.2.) His plans for visiting Glacier National park and their visiting there.